<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>mbrt blog</title>
    <link>https://blog.mbrt.dev/</link>
    <description>Recent content on mbrt blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.150.1</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blog.mbrt.dev/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Resurrecting valuable expired domains</title>
      <link>https://blog.mbrt.dev/posts/domain-resurrect/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.mbrt.dev/posts/domain-resurrect/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I processed a large fraction of the Internet on a single machine, trying to find
some valuable but forgotten domain names to buy (probably 25 years too late).
Here&amp;rsquo;s the story of what I found and how I did it, and &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; the story of
&lt;strong&gt;why&lt;/strong&gt; I decided to try, because I don&amp;rsquo;t know myself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Spoiler alert&lt;/strong&gt;: If you just want to know whether there is indeed something,
and you should scramble to scoop it up to become a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_name_speculation&#34;&gt;domain-flipper&lt;/a&gt;
billionaire, hold your horses: I believe there isn&amp;rsquo;t much. The following
sections are more focused on the engineering side, so if you only care about the
conclusion, skip to &lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.mbrt.dev/posts/domain-resurrect/#results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glassdb: transactional object storage</title>
      <link>https://blog.mbrt.dev/posts/transactional-object-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.mbrt.dev/posts/transactional-object-storage/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was frustrated by the gap between stateless and stateful applications in the
cloud. While I could easily spin up a stateless application as a &amp;ldquo;serverless&amp;rdquo;
function in any major cloud provider and pretty much forget about it, persisting
data between requests was a game of pick two among three: cheap, strongly
consistent, portable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Could I solve portability and lack of transactions myself with &lt;em&gt;a single
client-side solution?&lt;/em&gt; I thought it would be possible through object storage
(e.g. &lt;a href=&#34;https://aws.amazon.com/s3/&#34;&gt;AWS S3&lt;/a&gt;), which is strongly consistent,
ubiquitous and cheap.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Better design docs</title>
      <link>https://blog.mbrt.dev/posts/better-design-docs/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.mbrt.dev/posts/better-design-docs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What&lt;/strong&gt; is a design document? &lt;strong&gt;When&lt;/strong&gt; is it useful to have one? &lt;strong&gt;How&lt;/strong&gt; to
make it useful? These are the questions I&amp;rsquo;m going to address in this post. The
goal is to provide some bite sized, easy to remember guidelines. My promise to
you is that after this post, you&amp;rsquo;ll be faster and more effective in making and
reviewing designs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a written version of a talk I gave at my current employer. Since it was
well received and helped a few folks, I decided to make it more available.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Maybe you don&#39;t need SRE</title>
      <link>https://blog.mbrt.dev/posts/no-need-sre/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.mbrt.dev/posts/no-need-sre/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Running a Site Reliability Engineering (SRE) organization correctly is difficult
and expensive. Spare the frustration, perhaps what you need is Sysadmins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since the term was coined by Ben Treynor in 2003 at Google, lots of ink was
spent on praising SRE practices. Not enough on &lt;em&gt;when&lt;/em&gt; it is appropriate to have
SREs. This post is a take on that angle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: I was an SRE at Google and this piece represents only my own views.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Engineering a chess match against my brother</title>
      <link>https://blog.mbrt.dev/posts/chess-eng/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.mbrt.dev/posts/chess-eng/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the story of me trying to win a game of chess against my brother. A
single freaking game. What&amp;rsquo;s so special about it? Am I good at chess? Not at
all. Did I improve at my game in the process? Also no. Is it a story about &amp;ldquo;the
journey rather than the destination&amp;rdquo;? Not really. Did I at least have fun in
the process? Not so sure. This is the story of me trying to be unconventional
at probably the most studied game in existence and using my software
engineering background for something that probably doesn&amp;rsquo;t need it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying container networking</title>
      <link>https://blog.mbrt.dev/posts/container-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.mbrt.dev/posts/container-network/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the last year, at work I had multiple chances to debug how containers work.
Recently we had to solve some networking problems a customer had with
&lt;a href=&#34;https://kubernetes.io/&#34;&gt;Kubernetes&lt;/a&gt;, and I decided I wanted to know more. Once
the problem was solved, I spent more time on investigating what is actually
going on under the hood. After seeing the wonderful
&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/wyqoi52k5jM&#34;&gt;Eric Chiang&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;https://youtu.be/b3XDl0YsVsg&#34;&gt;Laurent Bernaille&lt;/a&gt; talks, and reading through
the very informative posts by
&lt;a href=&#34;https://blog.lizzie.io/linux-containers-in-500-loc.html&#34;&gt;Lizzie Dixon&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://jvns.ca/blog/2016/10/10/what-even-is-a-container/&#34;&gt;Julia Evans&lt;/a&gt;
(that I really really recommend), I got enough information about how a
container is created and managed. I&amp;rsquo;m going to rip off and mix some stuff from
their awesome posts in the first part of mine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Antifurto: home made security camera</title>
      <link>https://blog.mbrt.dev/posts/antifurto/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.mbrt.dev/posts/antifurto/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In February 2014 I had a very unpleasant surprise after coming back home from a
weekend in Berlin. Me and my girlfriend found out our apartment upside down
because of burglars. We suffered the loss not only of many of our belongings,
but worse, of our safety. We didn&amp;rsquo;t feel safe in our home and we didn&amp;rsquo;t feel
safe to leave it - not even for half an hour - for the fear to come back and
find somebody inside. It was with this mood that I started this project: totally
motivated to do something about it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ripgrep code review</title>
      <link>https://blog.mbrt.dev/posts/ripgrep/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.mbrt.dev/posts/ripgrep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been playing around with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.rust-lang.org&#34;&gt;Rust&lt;/a&gt; for a year and a
half, and the best part of it, like many others say, has been the very helpful
community. There are a lot of online resources that help you to get started: the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doc.rust-lang.org/book/&#34;&gt;Rust book&lt;/a&gt;, the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doc.rust-lang.org/nomicon/&#34;&gt;Rustonomicon&lt;/a&gt; and many
&lt;a href=&#34;https://this-week-in-rust.org/&#34;&gt;blog posts&lt;/a&gt; and
&lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/tagged/rust&#34;&gt;stack overflow questions&lt;/a&gt;.
After I learned the
basics I felt a bit lost though. I couldn&amp;rsquo;t find enough resources for
intermediate-level-Rustaceans. I&amp;rsquo;m a C++ developer in my daily job, and so I&amp;rsquo;m
used with books like &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aristeia.com/books.html&#34;&gt;Effective C++&lt;/a&gt; from
Scott Meyers, the &lt;a href=&#34;https://herbsutter.com/&#34;&gt;Herb Sutter&amp;rsquo;s blog&lt;/a&gt; and a lot of
online resources that always helped me with advanced C++ topics (that are a
lot&amp;hellip; :sigh:). Those resources teach you how to get the best from the
language, how to use it properly, and how to structure your code to be more
clear and effective. Those resources are not completely absent in the Rust
community, but neither common.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keygenning with KLEE [doar-e]</title>
      <link>https://blog.mbrt.dev/posts/keygen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blog.mbrt.dev/posts/keygen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was published in the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://doar-e.github.io&#34;&gt;Diary of a reverse-engineer&lt;/a&gt; as a guest post:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://doar-e.github.io/blog/2015/08/18/keygenning-with-klee/&#34;&gt;Keygenning with KLEE&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
